all right then any questions about Thank
You Casilla I'm enjoy this meditation
thank you I have question what you know
what
wait how could she shouldna Kapoor
furniture you had the other lien which
way that said take away dog or she
should openly go fool ameesha Patel
ameesha Olivia your your face she means
yeah yo ting dementia little angel
with algo sucio turn out the disruption
in the cambium fascia the whole said to
finish enjoy your Santa are on the city
or central cool the whole Hui Hui
Cassandra new una boda Yahoo Co Co Co Co
she the for me and Archie no Yoli cuts
weak cilia the John so she said when I
was having this meditation when I went
back to the past lives
I felt like my meditation becomes like
very comprehensive one for example like
it's including all kinds of skills like
the listing meditation or analyzing
meditation or focusing meditation etc
for example I remember in my previous
life I was a teacher and I was teaching
my students for example I was teaching
them about three kinds of sufferings so
when I was teaching them three kinds of
sufferings its kind of listing you know
these three kinds of sufferings to my
students but then I also had all these
things that I did wrong in my past life
so I had to do four powers in my
meditation so is it correct or wrong if
I'm doing this yeah nice nice good
question
so in Buddhist and we recognize three
kinds of meditation right check home
shower go and check on Joe comb she say
she'll go check on Joe calm okay shotgun
means I like to call it making a list
like it's going through a process
reviewing a process and then check ohm
is what problem you can call it problem
solving meditation you know you take a
question in your life and you resolve it
during the meditation and then jog on
yeah single-pointed meditation so what
kind of meditations do you think the
first eight are
while you're in each one yes Joe commits
single-pointed okay the eighth the
eighth meditations and again I I was
thinking to read you the warning from
k2j there's a warning from Kate about
don't get off the elevator in the first
eight meditations keep going to the
ninth then so that's Joe gum what about
the check in your past life what kind of
meditation yeah it's kind to I guess you
could call it a list but it's for me
it's kind of a problem-solving I'm
trying to figure out how did I plant
those seeds you see so I asked myself a
question that's our chi gong ask
yourself a question and then go figure
it out
you know how how did I get these seeds
why am I seeing my Lama like that and
then I go into my past life and check
what I did and what vidiians saying is
that during the past life meditation I
think mainly she feels like she's can be
wandering around different kinds of
meditation sometimes focusing on
something sweet she did sometimes going
through the different steps of purifying
seeds or enhancing seeds and then
sometimes solving problems in past life
maybe and I think that's great the whole
purpose of the eight meditations is
called so SEL means it's a difficult
word to translate but it means it's the
word that's it's used for gymnasts or
circus performers who can jump backwards
and flip over and and they show off
their itself
it's called showing off your so your
flexibility so
we're showing off our meditative
flexibility mental flexibility and when
we do the last three parts of the lion
stance which we'll do next time which is
called tug yell kittens in you you
practice so you you're gonna go to level
eight then you're gonna go the air
conditioner real fast then you come back
to seven okay then you go back to the
air conditioner real fast or come back
to six go to nine come back to fire and
like that okay we'll practice that okay
so everything about this meditation
itself it's meant to build up it's like
doing different yoga poses to stretch
your body and make your mind more
flexible okay so you can learn to
control your mind okay the puppy-dog of
your mind okay so I like it I think it's
cool okay if you have time you might get
fired from your job
okay other question thank you
um during the meditation we will imagine
that some kind of the quality that that
our teacher haves so I just wonder what
is the difference between the the seed
that we can see somebody else has such
kind of qualities versus this we our own
we have the quality of ourselves what is
the difference between that yeah and it
possible how how to switch those seeds
so I can see myself have that quality
yeah and we had a good question so we're
focusing on the seeds in in today I was
focusing on the states my llama takes a
lot of personal responsibility so right
now they're taking some personal
responsibility
that's why they're not here and so I can
observe this personal responsibility but
I don't have it or it's not as strong
so what Edmunds question is it's almost
like because they're our teacher it kind
of means we don't have that call too yet
maybe if we had it we would be their
teacher so I don't have it but I have
the seeds right or I couldn't see it in
my teacher right so I have sleeping
seeds they call Buckland yellow Buckland
yah
it means sleeping seeds
so what Edmonds question is how do I
wake those seeds up so I can see this
quality in myself and the best way is to
picture them opening into your Loma and
go through your past life experiences so
the best way to wake up the sleeping
seeds is to do this meditation that's
the secret meaning goal of the
meditation okay
so by thinking about the seeds you
already have you will wake them up and
you'll see them open in yourself and the
first part of getting the seeds that's
strong is to appreciate them think about
them then slowly you'll see yourself
start to become like that in fact you
can't stop it if you keep doing this
meditation you will become a very sweet
responsible person by accident
okay one more question then we have to
go to the diamond cutter at the sutra
we'll never finish
thank you yes you that I'm wondering
about the crystal of sugar and if that
should be outside of ourselves or can it
be in our heart can it be in our heart
Lamas heart is the same as the emptiness
or is it something different yeah good
question so as I mentioned previously if
you find your mind is wandering too much
or you have trouble focusing there's a
tradition to focus on something tiny
like a grain of sand or a grain of sugar
and there's a cool meditation 16 levels
of sugar grains
it's a kadampa meditation is called the
Kadampa sixteen and I got that
transmission from a very very high Lama
and you can after a while in the grain
of sugar you go inside of grainy sugar
inside the grain of sugar and there's a
different Lama in each grain of sugar so
personally when I do the meditation I I
see the heart as sort of a dark space
not a bad way not in a bad way but just
like in a your bedroom at night when all
the lights are off like I feel
comfortable and at home I don't feel
scared or something it's not tim-tim er
Tamera it's not it's not that kind of
cutoff scary darkness it's kind of a
comfortable I'm in my bed darkness under
the blankets and then I I bring the
sugar crystal inside that space so for
me the space is about this big of course
there's no space
sighs in your meditation but it feels
about this big to me and then I put the
sugar grain inside there but if you
wanted to use the principle of tiny
means focus yeah you could like put the
emptiness of the boo-boo Lama in your
real Lama in their heart as big as a
grain of sugar yeah you could play with
that and it helps you focus when you
feel distracted if you start to feel
nervous or tight in your chest or
something or like that if you're a
person who tends to get more nervous
there's two kind of personality right
Rajas and Tamas if you're more sleepy
personality which was me you can do a
lot of hard work in your heart small
crystal but if you're more nervous
personality you might want to do it at
your navel okay or here this is medium
nervousness this is highly nervous and
the navel is low nervous so if you
feeling kind of shaky bring it down to
the navel okay
and expand it a little bit make it like
a baseball or orange fruit okay if you
feel sleepy
tighten it up into a single point a
kagura okay like that all right let's go
to will do more questions tomorrow okay
and in the future
we reached can you put the verse up you
guys
we reached boot budem oh wait I think
Jazmin owes us something
Oh after the break what we do yesterday
after the break okay
after the break she's gonna teach us the
Chinese okay
maybe tomorrow you have to recite the
Chinese to get in the class okay the
Chinese is very very old
okay very very old it was translated I
think almost six seven hundred years
before well call it a few hundred years
before Tibet
okay six seven hundred years before some
couple it was translated into Chinese
kumara Jima and later by Swenson right
doctor would took me to see kumara ji
was stupa he he was a great translator
from India who lived in Xi'an and when
he passed away he said if if I ever
translated something wrong if I never
translated something wrong then after
you burned my body my tongue should be
intact and it was and it's still there
okay but Buddha six meanings of the
bubble so Buddha Buddha means Bubba
I used to teach people boo doo dum
because I I missed I misread the
combination of letters this DB is
extremely rare but DD h is very common
anyway
it's tiny in the printing what group do
we on we didn't say yesterday I should
have said we're on the 3rd group okay
the first group was house what's your
world like star cataract and lamb okay
and then second group was how do you
taste it oh I always taste it wrong I
always think the husband yelling at me
from the husband okay that's how I taste
my world
I blame other people and I blame other
circumstances okay that's how I taste my
world like a razor okay with honey over
it okay then a third group yeah what's
wrong with this world and that I did I
should have mentioned yesterday there
are two big divisions to group number
three there are two big parts to group
number three okay the first one is the
other Shia and it means yeah they do so
that represents impermanence okay so the
first problem of our life is that
nothing lasts especially good things
they don't last okay the second problem
is the pain of life so the bubble always
represents pain okay and you would think
it would represent impermanence
but it's pain okay so the do represents
the problem of life
that it it goes too fast okay and bubble
represents the suffering of life okay
always so by the way I like to give you
the explanation of the Sanskrit right
especially the cognates what English
words come from that word and
this is simple onomatopoeia
okay it sounds it sounds like what it is
but okay that's good in in linguistics
is called onomatopoeia but but bubbles
make this sound there's some other
famous examples in Sanskrit I thought to
give you some for fun okay these are
from a book called Sanskrit grammar by
Dwight Whitney he was from Yale he lived
over a hundred years ago and if you want
to study Sanskrit his book is the
greatest by far okay from Yale 120 years
ago something a little bit more and then
his student was Franklin Edgerton who
was also at Yale and Banaras Hindu
University which is the greatest place
in the world to study Sanskrit and
John's organization just bought a piece
of land next to the university to build
a school for Sanskrit and I'd like to
thank them as two weeks ago I think
so you're that's we give their DCI gives
programs at that University once a year
and so now you can go study there if you
want it's embarrassing okay
and there'll be Sanskrit Tibetan Chinese
if you guys want and you can be immersed
in the local language there are more
Sanskrit scholars there than anywhere in
the world when first time I gave a talk
there they took me in a room with 30 of
them and they made me recite Sanskrit
luckily it was something I had already
memorized so from the bhagavad-gita so
luckily we passed
so anyway adjutants student was named
Samuel Atkins at Princeton and that was
my teacher so you are of a very great
lineage of Sanskrit also alright anyway
Whitney said here's some out of my peers
you guess okay here's the Sanskrit
boop-boop-boop-boop this is from the
Veda okay from the Vedas boo boo come on
dog bark okay how about Cisco Cisco
Cisco arrow sound okay sheesh good how
about by the way JB except it's Vedic so
I'll give you a clue it's the same as a
continent name
come on four continents
what's our continent Kong Jambu say
jumbo so the world we live in in
Buddhism in Buddhist cosmology is called
Jambu and that's the sound that a
wishing tree fruit makes when it falls
in the ocean - boom - boo okay these are
all onomatopoeia that means Jambu same
okay it's very important in vagi or
Guinea practice okay
ancient okay I'll stop
how about kick it kick it that's your
heart when you're scared it means good
okay all right why are we talking about
that good Buddha but good but good okay
Bubba okay all right it's onomatopoeia
all right Bobo has how many meanings
oh so the bubble is suffering and the do
is impermanence okay good six meanings
for the bubble number one
Master Camilla Sheila massive Ossipon do
Jame on Sheba
Tony Loma they just emphasize listen the
bubble means suffering okay it means
life is suffering okay and they they
don't go a lot into it okay but they say
the bubble means suffering
okay $10 Amba meaning number two he says
please note this is not wah wah means a
bubble also but that means a bubble in
the ocean or in your green drink okay a
water a bubble in the water
it's called whooah in Tibetan but this
is chuh board this is a different kind
of bubble he says this bubble is a
bubble caused by rainfall or you spilled
your coffee and it this bubble is one on
the dry land okay it's important this
boot Buddha is not a bubble in the lake
or in the ocean or in the green drink
it's after you spill the green drink and
it's a bubble on the ground that comes
very it's even faster than the normal
bubble right a bubble on the ocean can
last for a few seconds a bubble when you
spill your green drink if you're lucky
enough to spill your green drink it will
disappear quickly okay it just lasts for
a split second okay so $10 Amba this is
meaning number two he says oh this is a
this is not a water bubble this is this
Sanskriti sir a bubble on the ground
very fragile
and if you think about it it comes from
of causes there has to be a rain cloud
above there has to be a earth waiting
for the rain below and there has to be
falling of the rain to the earth or you
can say green drink okay but something
has to be above something has to be
below and something has to move okay
causes dependent origination so for him
this represents the causes of perception
okay especially in the Wheel of Life
there's a John Brady over there
there's Geshe Michaels eye over here and
there's movement between the earth and
the sky okay and that creates instance
of consciousness that only lasts very
instantaneously okay I can only see John
for so many moments and then something
will separate us karma will separate us
okay so for $10 rumba he's the pessimist
right everything is suffering okay so
the bubble is like this causes that
caused awareness of your family and of
your country and of your body and they
they come and go very quickly you lose
things okay all right suffering
suffering of loss okay meaning number
three this is Camila Sheila and quench
Oh Tammy do me okay two of them they
talked about this third one they say if
you think about it
[Music]
bubbles are made of water okay there's
water in the green drink okay
by the way can you bring up the picture
of the meditation there's water in the
green drink there's water in the bubble
in a different form right in a different
format and then there's water in the air
after you pop the bubble right the water
spreads into the air and we have a
picture here which Nick is carving
there's a joke in Tibetan they say don't
carve it just display yeah okay so the
left side of the bubble is water the
right side of the bubble is water and
the green drink that you spilled to form
the bubble was water so for Camila
Sheela the bubble represents three
states of water three states of water as
rain as a bubble on the ground and then
as water in the air after you pop the
bubble three states of water the middle
one is a bubble the first one is a
raindrop and the third one is the these
little pieces of bubble as they fly off
in the air okay so the three states of
the bubble where the bubble came from
where the bubbles going and where the
bubble is okay
they're all water and he says it relates
to the three parts that we know Shanti
Shanti Shanti
okay yoga teachers love to sing chant
[Music]
try see crazy
that means peace peace peace right it
comes from the Upanishads
but it refers to the three kinds of
suffering three kinds of pain okay three
kinds of pain number one you know pain
of pain had
number two paint of change a good dinner
and then the pain of life which is
getting older yeah inevitable death
aging okay so for him the three states
of the water are the three kinds of pain
okay the water in the raindrop or the
green drink the water in the bubble and
the water after the bubble breaks
he also related to
the three classical kinds of feeling
which it feels good feels bad feels
neutral now you tell me how the three
kinds of suffering we just talked about
relate to the three divisions of
suffering I'm sorry
feeling good feeling bad feeling neutral
feeling okay first kind of pain bad
feeling okay bad second kind of pain
yeah it starts out feeling good like a
good dinner okay the classical example
in Scripture is a good dinner go out for
a good dinner like Adams gonna take
Katie to a nice dinner on the way back
to wherever okay what about neutral yeah
neutral is the suffering that we have
our whole life you know right now it's
going on you can't feel it your body's
getting older during this class there's
a joke in the monastery you meet your
Lama where have you been Oh Lama you
should be happy why I was in yoga class
oh how long oh today I did two hours you
know they're like why'd you do that well
I want to stay healthy huh ah you are
two hours closer to your death you got
older during the yoga class you go to
enough yoga classes you'll be too old to
do yoga okay so one of the sad things
you see all the yoga teachers who can't
do yoga anymore okay and so do your yoga
you should do your yoga but but don't go
crazy you know don't say oh look I can
do a handstand you know later you won't
be able to get up out of the bed okay so
be have a good sense about your yoga
okay I'm just doing this to keep myself
going as long as possible it's really
depressing when you're my age and people
say oh you look really good for 65 I'm
like thanks
okay so your body's getting older okay
so anyway that's all contained in the
bubble for master Carla Sheila point you
tell me do me okay the nature of the
bubble is pain okay
pain waiting to happen pain that already
happened or pain disguised as happiness
okay
then they quote the Buddha who said any
kind of feeling is pin
okay fourth one I think am i right okay
those same authors say look to a infant
what's infant meaning Buddhism yeah
someone who hasn't seen emptiness is
called a in American English we say he's
acting like a two-year-old and today
Nick is acting like a two-year-old
it means immature or something okay
that's exactly the word Chiba abala
in Sanskrit it means two-year-old baby
two year old babies understanding of
physics describes the state of all
humans who are not an ayah seriously
okay it's actually worse than that but
okay so they say to infants it seems
like you know there's a difference
between a coffee and a green drink my
green drink is purple today okay so to
an infant who hasn't seen emptiness okay
directly this one looks worse
this one looks better this one looks
like it giving me a bad feeling and this
one looked like it gave me a good
feeling but to an aria they're exactly
the same
okay to an aria all feeling is pain you
know okay
in the time I took to drink this is I'm
one drink closer to my death
whether I'm drinking green drink or
coffee I'm still one drink closer to my
death
okay got it that's the way in Aria
thinks they used their time every minute
of their time okay
they need time don't waste an August
time now to prove that point number four
which is that all feeling is pain they
quote the Buddha okay they quote the
Buddha very famous quarter woke up Gita
Mona say kore WA Kopke seminar dear WA
name young young Mayan sitting on the
tip of the needle of samsara there is no
happiness there is no pleasure okay
I always think of this thumbtack we put
on my teachers chair in the school when
I read this verse did you do that maybe
that's an Arizona thing we would put a
thumb tack on the teachers chair they
would sit down and go so anyway when
your butts on the thumbtack of samsara
there's no happiness
[Music]
what it means is you're always on the
thumbtack your butt's always on the
thumbtack
I'm sensor I was curious they always say
the Buddhist said that and I went to
find it and I found it it's a little bit
different this quarter okok it said some
young they were nene-chan same it
and it comes from a sutra called the
sadhana must merge up Astana and you can
check it out someday
ok don't forget that it does come from
the Buddha it really was from the Buddha
probably one of his students put a thumb
tack on it ok all right
ABCD we're on number fire ok
master kamila Sheila goes a little bit
further he says any object which starts
and stops any object which exhibits
starting or stopping will cause you pain
okay the third kind of pain how about
you cheeky dunya right the pain of being
alive is is communicated to you by any
object which begins at all
relationships children house job country
okay they all have a beginning they'll
have an end okay they're all talking to
you you know I'm a thumbtack up on your
bottom all right
Geshe Michael added number six which is
duh I mean the bubble is impermanent
also okay it doesn't last very long so
although although it's supposed to
represent suffering in the classical
texts it also obviously represents
impermanence bubbles don't last very
long and bubbles can have a look of
solidity a little bit okay if you're a
surfer where is this surfer here yeah
yeah if you're a surfer you know the
foam on the water can can look solid
sometimes okay then you hit it with your
face and it's like a pillow okay or in
Hawaii it's a reef okay but anyway it
gives a sense of solidity but there's no
solidity
so that's illusion also okay we've
finished the bubble all right we have
some commercial advertisements birthday
boy and his lady of the song
you
earning everyone
that was my before and after coffee
voice I will make this short in great
part because I don't want to interrupt
your inner silence and retreat but we've
been asked to let you know of some of
our amazing projects that we are
undertaking here at Diamond Mountain and
this is an opportunity for us to ask for
your help and thus your seat in the
success of Diamond Mountain
one of our main projects right now as
you may know is an extensive
transportation plan we would like to
improve your experience here at Diamond
Mountain both here in the classrooms and
getting to your houses it's about a one
and a half kilometer walk it's a very
dusty road it is very rocky road even to
your houses is very steep and somewhat
dangerous at times and we are trying to
improve that we are building now upon a
very very generous donation by dr. Wu
and we want to thank them
[Applause]
[Music]
thank you so on top of dr. Wu's generous
donation we have been asked to raise
$200,000 ourselves go to the next slide
there we are and do to everyone's
generosity over the last 10 days I'm
happy to say that we are 50% of the way
there
that isn't a really really amazing at
such a short time so we're still
pitching that we still need to raise
another $100,000 which I'm very
confident we will and what we'd like to
do is offer naming things as you know as
Melissa spoke about this we can name
roads we can name valleys we can name
turnarounds name yoga tents name temples
so please talk to rob after the class
who's or Melissa who's going to be
handling the fundraising for that and if
anybody would like to contribute to the
building of diamond mountain but you
don't have $10,000 to donate Janice is
collecting smaller donations for from
the America group as well so that we can
all come together and have a bit of the
merit from building these roads next
slide so as we talked about a couple
days ago the ranch house formerly known
as the llama house a historic building
not only in southeastern Arizona and the
history of the United States but also a
historical building to Diamond Mountain
and it's in badly badly need of a new
roof the current roof that we have is a
bit of a fire hazard so we'd like to
replace that as soon as possible over
the past 10 10 days we've raised $13,000
so I'm confident that if we all come
together during this retreat we can
raise the remaining $17,000 for that
roof we also have the option if you
would like to plant the tree in memory
of a loved one or in celebration of an
occasion you're welcome to donate for a
tree and we'll be starting a big
tree-planting campaign we have some
permaculture experts coming in tomorrow
they're gonna walk with us over our 1000
acres maybe we'll drive some of that too
and they're gonna help us choose some
strategic places where we can plant the
trees where they can be of most benefit
so you can donate a tree and finally
we currently have I think 30 cottage
adopters or monthly donors just in the
past ten days ten more people signed up
to adopt a cottage so this is a really
beautiful way to be able to support a
specific cottage or diamond mountain in
general on a regular basis so as you
know things happen water pipes break
batteries run I don't know stop working
and it's nice to be able to when
somebody's in retreat just be able to go
to the store and buy a new battery so
you know you guys can continue having
electricity that we can fix the pipe no
problem so it's because of our cottage
adopters and daily donors that diamond
mountain has the ability to make these
changes immediately as the fixes come up
so if you'd like to build a deeper
connection with the cottage you're
staying at you're welcome to adopt your
cottage otherwise if you've just had a
pleasant experience if it's been
life-changing for you you're welcome to
become a dollar-a-day donor where you
will donate to a general fund and then
whatever is most needed by Diamond
Mountain at that time your donation will
go to fund that project so for for the
houses or Diamond mountain in general
you can let us know so I have a couple
of things that you can grab on your way
out of the temple today I have envelopes
for cash donations and checks you can
pick these up on your way out please put
your name your email address maybe your
house
so I can send you a proper thank-you
which I really love to do if you would
like to donate by credit card you can
either see me or you can see Rob after
class preferably tomorrow because then
we don't disturb your silence and your
retreat or you can grab this form and
you can fill it out and give it to us as
you leave and if you want to become a
cottage adopter or a dollar-a-day
donor then you can fill out this form in
as well give it to myself or Rob
tomorrow before you leave any questions
okay thank you everybody yeah
you
yes thank you so on the envelope your
name
the reason oh I'm sorry
Rob said it would be helpful if you make
a cash donation to please in addition to
your name and your email address put the
reason for the donation what project you
want the donation to go towards thank
you everybody I'd like to thank a CI for
being here without you Diamond Mountain
wouldn't exist so really really
appreciate it for that and thank you
cash flow for all that you do for us
okay we have one hour let's go around
the last three of the nine metaphors I
think right so we finished the group of
what's wrong with this liar it had two
parts
what's the two parts of a of a Shia the
do and the boo boo boo boo boo do the
bubbles okay first one means
impermanence second one means pain okay
good now we reach the last group the
fourth group it has three parts three
different metaphors what's the last
group why you should try to escape okay
why you should try to escape okay why
you should try to get out now okay in in
in Tibetan language they call kill wake
you go egg you means reasons you should
be sad about this world okay why you
should try to get out okay there's going
to be three images
I have a I've been you know watching how
fast we can go through this and we still
have a quarter of the Sutra to cover so
I propose we do five Kamla Sheila's
instead of four and so instead of
starting iron the gardener in the spring
we'll do a one more common law Sheila
class and I'll try to I would like to
translate the Sutra I mean that his
commentary the notes are 550 pages if I
could get some time I think I could
translate it or a big piece of it by the
spring so it's up to you guys to help me
get time okay
then if I don't get time I can't do it
so I'm very happy to help with you know
business stuff but you know jig may then
venerable Jigme learned to take stuff
off my she takes time away from me she
drives me everywhere if I Drive to the
college it's 24 minutes and she drives
me and I work in the back
you know and so you know if you can save
me time that you can have become like
Sheila if not you won't and I don't
think anyone else can do it right now in
the world so up to you okay all right I
love talking with you I love helping you
with your challenges but
it's also good if you can use the four
steps yourself and you know if you
really need help talk to me but you know
every kid has to grow up and at some
time you have to learn to use the four
steps and okay on you on your own but
I'm happy to give advice okay help but I
have to finish the other things also
okay so help me alright hmm and Rihanna
saves me a lot of time she she cooks
things for me shopping saves me a lot of
time after a tour I wake up in my house
and I go cappuccino and it's very silent
anyway usually there's ten people
waiting outside my room to give me a
cappuccino
okay dream five meanings okay I like the
Sanskrit the Sanskrit is Swapna Swapna
came it comes from the roots swaps what
means to sleep SDAP
it comes into the word some Sonia like
insomnia n means not somnium in sleepy
so Swapna became some nice okay so in
insomnia means cannot sleep okay
in Greek the sve changes to hy
and you get hypnosis meaning to put
someone into a sleep okay hip-hip no tis
okay so what hypno comes from Swapna
okay all right here we go first one
there's a principle with Kamala Sheila
Vasa bandeau about this last three okay
they say they represent son skirt does
what's her son's got done anything put
together by causes anything caused
really okay anything produced a good
translation of Sanskrit is produced okay
Avram - dove um sons good done okay sons
good that means all the stuff around us
which is not unchanging okay
sons kurta includes all things which are
not unchanging give me one unchanging
thing emptiness and empty space those
are two cheap ones okay some Buddhists
say facts are unchanging the sky is blue
as long as the sky is blue the fact is
unchanging okay like then alright so the
great masters who explained the diamond
cutter Sutra they like to say of the
last three right what are the last three
swapna vidyut and Abram right
Swapna dream video lightning and Abram
cloud they say these three represent
past present and future changing things
so the dream represents Sun scrotums
Sanskrit us which are past in the past
and then the lightning
present you know it's not like something
that happened yesterday or something
happened tomorrow
it's just attrition and it's done it's a
present moment thing okay then clouds we
don't know it's going to happen tomorrow
diamond we don't know exactly the
weather okay so that's a future thing
okay
and here we go on their explanation okay
dream number one on the dream
Master Camilla Sheila says okay the
dream represents
changing things from your past okay and
why is it a good example
because things from your past cannot do
anything now okay
things from your past cannot do anything
now
your ex-wife or ex-husband is gone okay
they can't give you trouble anymore now
okay
usually alright so gone okay and and
they cannot do anything now and Kamala
Sheila in the same breath says like the
second husband okay
very similar to the second husband who's
the second husband
give me it like this I can't do anything
I need you start yelling at me okay I
didn't do anything we can call it the I
didn't do anything husband okay with the
boss it's because you didn't do anything
okay so master Kamla Sheila says things
of the past which cannot do anything to
you they cannot hurt you for example
that husband is gone he lives in Nevada
now he's got remarried
you know it's over okay cannot affect
you now in a similar way the husband
who's not coming from you is a phantom
like a phantom from the past cannot do
anything to you okay
can I hurt you if you decide to be hurt
that's your decision but that they don't
have any power by the way the word in
Tibetan here is Jin lop which normally
means blessing but in philosophy it
means can do something okay can change
something
Jin lop means change make a change
affect the change so things of the past
son skirt does which are from 2013 they
can't do anything now okay
they are like a dream after you wake up
okay
last night I was in the dream I was
translating for some big Lama in a big
auditorium and I couldn't understand
anything and I was really upset you know
I was like making excuses in the dream
you know and then when I woke up I'm
like and also nobody dreamed okay things
of your past which hurt you they're gone
they are like the second husband all
right Johnny I'm shepper oh by the way
in the first one master Kamla Sheila
says don't forget the husband represents
the two kinds of emptiness what are the
two kinds of emptiness things and people
okay don't get upset at the weather
don't get upset at traffic those are
things okay you also created things
usually it's people who upset us but
things can also upset us the weather how
hard it is when the electricity breaks
in your cottage
okay you have to remember the emptiness
of things okay all right Johnny on
shepper meaning number two meaning
number two
how you relate to the past you should
understand it's like a dream okay
the husband who hurt you in 2013
didn't exist then either okay doesn't
exist now gone but even in 2013 he
didn't exist okay which one
I didn't do anything for don't we sit
down you started yelling at me
okay got it that husband didn't exist in
2013 and of course doesn't exist now
meaning number three $10 Amba he says if
you think about it most of the images
you see in a dream relate to something
in your past okay he says there's an
automatic connection between dreams and
things that happen to you three years
ago four years ago ten years ago when
you were a kid oftentimes your dreams
are repeating good or bad experiences
you had as a child or traumas in your
life like that they keep coming back in
the dreams he says therefore the dream
is connected automatically to pass
things okay and you cannot keep them
and in that way it represents to present
things you see so
even your family your house your job
your position your own body your
intelligence are already like the past
you cannot keep them okay
they are like past things already in the
present they are already like past
things you cannot keep them even if you
want to right
even if you hold on to them if you
physically hold on to your partner you
cannot keep them in this world okay they
will leave so in a way the things you
have now are already passing okay unless
you learn how to plant Rico reinvest
your seeds reinvest you see okay you're
supposed to be karma Cree investors
right every time something good come to
you share it with somebody else then you
get more a Buddha who lives in a Buddha
paradise forever it's just a great car
McCree investor okay they learn how to
do it and that's why buddha paradise
lasts forever
they keep reinvesting they make ten
dollars from karma they always give away
five Geisha should I give away ten it's
okay keep five have some fun okay
because five is gonna become fifty okay
it's okay
keep half keep some for yourself that's
okay have fun go out to dinner go see a
movie okay you don't Buddhism doesn't
mean sacrifice okay it doesn't mean that
those Buddhist in the Buddha paradise do
they look like they're sacrificing you
know they're okay they spend five
dollars they go out for a nice pizza and
then they give five dollars to a
homeless person on the way to the pizza
parlor
okay that's that's good because the five
is gonna become 50 you're still gonna
come out ahead
you good still gonna make five hundred
percent okay don't worry about it okay
so have fun have a fun life Buddhism
doesn't mean you're you're always like I
can't eat pizza it costs too much it's
okay okay have a nice pizza and then
give give to half the pizza to somebody
okay all right
third fourth one right okay this is
coins ultimate do me and he wants to go
to master chandrakirti okay he says
let's go read master chandrakirti who
most famous book is called entering the
middle way and the middle way here is
the gardener's book that we're going to
do two classes from now because we're
gonna do I think we should do like the
fourth part of the comely Sheena and
then review the whole thing next time we
meet okay then then we remember
everything because I don't remember part
1 or part 2 myself okay and by the way
the fourth part of the diamond cutter
Sutra the Buddha repeats himself alone
he repeats things from the first part
the second part and we have to study why
like did he forget he taught the first
part or is there a deeper reason why he
repeats himself okay you can guess all
right okay here chandrakirti
you
this is difficult
all right he wants to talk about your
reaction to things in a dream okay
chunda cootie says look things can be a
dream but you still have a reaction to
them okay Geshe Michael is still nervous
when he wakes up about he couldn't
translate okay chandrakirti's example is
for monks who are dreaming about
beautiful ladies in the dream and of
course you can have strong feelings
during a dream okay so things from the
past which are gone which represent the
second husband okay which doesn't exist
still those things which don't exist can
give you strong feelings okay
and in fact
all negative feelings come from things
that don't exist
all negative feelings come from
misunderstanding right stars in the
night
so things can make you feel something
although they're not real okay
you can have a worry about the future
which is false or you can worry about I
don't know you can be really jealous
person who who thinks your wife is
running around with somebody and it's
all false but still it can make your
hair fall out okay and put a wrinkle on
your face okay then chandrakirti likes
to say this wasn't my idea it was Naggar
to this idea okay in his wisdom and
there's a great commentary called lamp
of wisdom written by above Aviv eka okay
and if we have time someday we should
read it okay lower middle way mother
book okay master Baba vivica's lamp on
wisdom okay mmm they all relate to how
pass things are similar to empty things
okay so when we talk about a dream we're
emphasizing past experiences traumas of
the past happy events of the past and
those
Vence and those people in the dream are
insubstantial in the same way that the
second husband is insubstantial doesn't
really exist it doesn't exist anymore in
the husband's case he never existed
never will never could in the past it
was like it did exist but now it's
almost the same status as the husband
get it okay a yelling husband in a dream
is very similar to a yelling husband in
the kitchen
they're both don't exist anymore never
did in the kitchen okay all right that's
a difficult one and of course
Geshe Michael added number five what to
Geshe Michael add he always does the
obvious one a dream isn't permanent you
wake up okay and thinks in a dream are
not real okay so really the dream is
representing both impermanence and
emptiness okay got it
so that one's so obvious that the great
commentators didn't talk about it now we
go to present changing things okay now
we just did past because dreams are
mostly about the past what's the example
yeah video to save you dude V means very
much VI means very much in sanskrit VI
means very much it's an abbreviation of
DVI TV which means double okay what
CentOS is lasting
Santos TV ad okay the director of our
Sanskrit project in India his last name
is Divya ad which means double nor it
means he's a Brahman okay sometimes it
means born again okay so do we means
double and the D drop sound and becomes
VI
so VI means very much okay V do you dude
you already had but it was a long time
ago do you
for depo lamb okay so so video means
double bright double bright
lightening okay lightning it's the
modern Hindi word for electricity by the
way okay
the electricity company in India is
called video okay all right mmm those of
you who studied DCI a level nine and
already forgot it level eight
I forgot what's lower what is lovely
yeah leadership and we said in there
the fourth perfection causes Duty what's
the fourth perfection yeah like being
happy when you work you know you Diamond
Mountain director and you're sweating
all day
Michael Dunn's are pretty good at that
he doesn't get grumpy did I know about
and he's cheerful so it means cheerful
if you're cheerful the karmic result is
you become a leader okay
and the gardener calls it video and like
electric leader you become an electric
leader okay okay now I was worrying
about something in in history the nine
examples can't be called the nine
examples for illusion and then the
impermanent ones are only eight
and of course it disturbed me a lot so I
went fishing and the reason the nine
illusion examples became a impermanent
examples you want to take a guess two of
them got joined together huh
yeah the lightning in the clown who said
then I'll give you a pat on the back
okay yeah so Milarepa used them and the
fifth dynam who is a great scholar he
shortened them to it so you might see
eight examples of impermanence
it's the nine just got shortened to
eight okay you don't care anyway I do
okay number one how many examples for
four meanings for lightning okay
four meanings to lightning
Master Camilla Sheila difficult okay
difficult lightning represents emptiness
because it is not one thing and it is
also not many parts either okay
lightning is not a single thing and
lightning is not all of its parts put
together either
okay it's called what's it called in
Tibetan Nick cheek to jaw to jaw
okay you have to say it low tone
children
Adam children okay the two means to my
mini ok cheater down okay so this is an
ancient proof of emptiness things are
not themselves
and things are not all are also not all
their parts put together
it's like a Cohen it's like a confusing
statement okay and master Camila Sheila
says you want to understand the
lightning understand one or many the
proof of emptiness called
one or many
and I'll repeat what you know what
buddhist scripture says that people who
are the people who see emptiness are the
curious ones they want to know more okay
and after the five hundredth proof of
emptiness when someone starts to whine
about it somebody like the gardener will
say no the more intelligent people
Dharma IQ hi Dharma iq people they want
more proofs of emptiness they don't want
less okay guys now can you teach the
gajanan after that can you teach Kate up
Jase meditation on emptiness and 800
pages if I have time we can do it okay
it's amazing it's amazing okay but I
need time okay if we have time we can do
that one okay so good students in boot
in Buddhist tradition they want to know
more they show me another proof of
emptiness Kichler
you didn't understand last one I
understood lastly I want another one you
know just cause you ate vanilla ice
cream doesn't mean you don't want
chocolate ice cream okay all right
hmm so you have to chew on that my mom I
used to he used to say sometimes you
chew on that one why isn't lightning not
one thing and also not many things put
together okay
that's your problem okay that's your
assignment for next spring maybe to get
in the door you have to explain it
there's an easy answer if you did DCI
don't tell everybody okay number two $10
I remember he seems to always like to
cause trouble he says I think lightning
should be the future not the present
okay
I think lightning should be the future
not the present he contradicts vast
abandon he contradicts Camila Sheila I
guess he thinks he's smarter on or maybe
he just wants to cause trouble by the
way it's a it's a method in the
monastery for an older gay Shay to say
something wrong
to see if it stirs up somebody's brain
okay so they will come in the month they
will come in and say the Lightning
relates to the future to the younger
monks and the younger monks are like no
that's not what the book says he says
forget the book prove it to me tell me
why it's not the future
how many times did someone say to you
look Tim there's a lightning over there
and Tim's like where and you say but it
already lightning just a moment ago and
then Tim looks at the clown and waits
for the next one lightnings always
future you can't tell Tim wait over
there that was lightning he goes like
that and it's over already
right so $10 on the troublemaker he says
no lightning Czar's future keep your eye
over to that direction see that cloud
just keep your eye there it means it's
gonna come right it's future that's his
idea okay it still means something you
cannot hold on to
okay future plans future hopes okay oh
I'm gonna invest in the stock market and
let make a lot of money or blah blah
blah okay without seeds right
future hopes are like trying to catch
lightning
okay number three point your 10-bit
doing me
he says you guys didn't really get it
exactly the point is
when you see a stroke of lightning it's
difficult to point out where did it
start you know which place in the cloud
did it start
right and then where did it go
afterwards you see so the idea is that
sometimes in Buddhism we say the path of
the ego the path of the eagle in the sky
okay they don't leave footprints Kota
moon days leave little poo-poos they
look like blessing pills if someone from
Diamond Mountain give you blessing pills
be careful okay same size same color
okay but lightning doesn't leave
anything okay no track no trace where
you can see if a coda Mooney was near
your house you can see all these
blessing pills on the ground but not the
Lightning right I can't see where it
came from and you can't see where it
went to
and he says
you ready we're gonna go deeper
he says the luminous images that come
out of the seeds in your mind okay the
Holograms that come out of the silver
seeds in your mind are the same as
lightning they are so quick you can't
really pinpoint when did they break out
of the steam and you can't really
pinpoint when did they cover your llama
right with the quality okay it's like
trying to pinpoint where lightning
started or where it stopped okay so when
we do they're lions dance level 9 we
slowed things down by about 4,000 times
okay the speed that the seeds are
opening it's about four thousand times
more than that okay we slow it down the
memory of your past life is a
reconstructed imagination but so is the
seed opening okay it's just pretending
okay
you have to meditate for years before
you can watch a seat open okay but you
can okay you can watch a single seat
open if you meditate a lot okay and it
should the idea like we were talking
about with the quality right Edmunds
question if you keep pretending you see
a seat open you one day it'll plant the
seed to see the seat open okay so we're
just pretending
we're also pretending that we're doing
the eight levels okay to get to the
first one it's difficult okay
somebody asked me guess not there's nine
stages in Camila Sheila's presentation
of meditation right the stages of
meditation
Bhavana Cromer right the big chart with
the monkey and the elephant
there are nine levels there also are
they the same no okay no well how do
they compare the first level of the
eight in the lion stance is equal to the
ninth level in camelina roughly okay you
got to get to come I see that to get
started on the eighth okay as far as the
meditation side concentration side
schemata okay we'll talk about it okay
people did here did three years three
months freedom retreat and they did a
cool thing during their retreat they
used to get together and say well which
level did you get to you know like I'm
up to four I think I'm on three okay if
you get to nine firmly on the schemata
side you can reach first Forum Romanum
good luck okay so we're just pretending
that we're at those levels because we're
trying to plant the seed okay all right
what happens if you get really good at
it and you don't know about level nine
what happens when you're reborn come on
Wonder Woman okay incredible hope what
do you call this guy I don't know you
know spider-man Iron Man etc okay okay
now you want to go deeper I just put
this in here for those deeper guys okay
the rest of you can have some coffee or
some there's some guys who just want to
go deeper all the time mister will want
to go deeper and then you want to go
deeper anyway he keeps me employed three
doors of freedom okay in in deep
Buddhism it's called the three Doors of
freedom
okay Nam talk awesome and it's a very
deep idea okay number topical say
momentum means the causes of a thing are
empty okay the causes of a thing are
empty that's the first door of freedom
if you see the causes of a thing are
empty okay gasoline that makes a car go
okay is there any power in the gasoline
it's like an aspirin yeah if you gave
other people rides in your car in the
past your gasoline will get you to
Tucson and if not there will be a
problem between here in Tucson okay will
I run out of gas
not necessarily because vanilla ice
cream karma can make chocolate ice cream
maybe your car will break down maybe you
will have a flat tire okay who put the
power in the petrol or the gas is you
okay how you gave people rise well guess
la that means in the future I could ride
a car without petrol yeah it's called a
solar car seriously you invented solar
okay all right you gave a few people
rides and you got gasoline with
pollution then you gave more people
rides you get solar okay you give a lot
of people rides you could just fly
by yourself okay seriously okay got it
the emptiness of the cause is called the
door of freedom that there's nothing
inside of anything okay Veronica told me
stop sticking my tongue out when I make
a big point okay
the first door of freedom is called
nothing is inside of anything same
American one is called number topical
tom bonney it's called the door freedom
named emptiness the door of freedom
called emptiness and that refers to the
thing which was caused okay going to
Tusa okay the cars was the gasoline okay
the gasoline is empty but the car is
also empty okay the car is also empty
and by the way the car is created by the
same common right you get people rides
probably with an umbrella or something
because the car keeps the rain off your
son that's called the second door of
freedom that caused a thing in the
present moment the emptiness of the
present moment thing that was caused uh
it's called the second door of freedom
second door to freedom okay got it
you okay guess what's the third door to
freedom huh yeah the result okay getting
to Tucson standing in the Tucson Airport
that's also empty the name the technical
name for that is the door of freedom
called no more hopes no more wishes no
more plans you're already in Tucson
that's also empty okay the emptiness of
there is own why are we talking about
this because we were talking about the
lightning that you can't say where it
came from
you can't say where it's going and you
almost can't say where it is the cause
the thing and the aftermath the result
are indefinable okay got it so they
relate to the three doors of freedom I
gave you those for free those are from
me okay mmm you want to go deeper
classically when you debate the three
doors to freedom they can relate to a
single thing okay the gasoline as a
cause the gasoline as a functioning
thing now and the gasoline as a result
of the refining process got it okay
the gasoline can be a cause of the car
going to Tucson the gasoline can be a
result of pipelines all over the world
we wanted to buy the land next door here
the guy is getting old he offered to
sell it to us the guy who sold us this
land offered us the land next door
behind her and we squeezed our usual
squeezing person and he gave a donation
and then we decided well we better check
the property you know carefully and we
found the oil parts three oil parts
underneath the ground one of them is
carrying a military aviation fuel from
Texas to Tucson and there's dangerous
stuff coming out of these parents you
know so we cancelled it okay it means
gasoline can be a result gasoline can be
a cause or gasoline can function now
okay one thing can be all three doors to
freedom okay why are you talking about
why you get so complicated everything
that is a cause is also a result and
everything that's a result is also a
cause okay when you meditate on the
seeds for your Lamas qualities it's a
result right but it also causes them you
to have them yourself every in Buddhism
every cause
is also a result okay that's why time
has no beginning okay that's why the
world has no beginning every result is a
cause and every cause is also a result
okay which came first the chicken on a
yes okay so that's just that's the three
doors of freedom if you think about it
you will understand function better you
will understand why aspirin works you
will understand why gasoline works okay
better the lower three schools of
Buddhism mind only logic schools and ah
be Dhamma school never got that far they
stopped they think gasoline does
something they think there's something
inside a gasoline that works okay they
couldn't get it okay that's why they're
lower score okay that's why they're
Norris Cole the three lower school's
abhidharma sutras and mind only the
reason they're alone a lower school one
of the reasons is they believe there's
something inside an aspirin that can
take away your heading and they believe
there's something inside of gasoline
that can make the car go they believe it
they can't understand that you put the
power in the gas or you put the power in
the aspirin
okay got it it feels like there's
something in the gas it feels like
there's something in the aspirin okay
and the highest goal says yeah you put
the power in the gas you put the power
in the aspirin that's why I spends don't
always work and that's why cars don't
always get to Tucson okay got him okay
so now your high school already Buddhism
had a huge split
the lower schools went south Sri Lanka
Burma Thailand
okay mind only and middle way never
reached those countries they don't have
the whole scriptures they don't have the
conger they don't have the Tingler
conquer and tenure took 25 years to
input John Brady finished in 4600 books
22 made it to Burma and Thailand Sri
Lanka okay all of them made it to China
and Tibet Nepal Japan Korea okay
Mongolia okay alright clowns you okay
not tired Stanley had a question that's
important enough to interrupt the whole
class he needs a microphone
sorry for the interruption hmm it's just
not so clear when you say the second
door of freedom and the third one you
said the second one is the thing that is
cost in the present moment yeah you say
the third one is the result which is
also the cost all things are all all
changing things are also resolves okay
but looking at the thing from the point
in in Tibetan or in Sanskrit the second
one is called more okay it means what is
the nature of the thing in the present
okay what is the nature of the thing in
the present its emptiness okay the first
order freedom is what is the nature of
its cause and the third door to freedom
is what is its nature of its result
okay so the second door of freedom is
what's the nature of the thing itself
now okay and the first one is what was
the nature of its cause and the third
one is what is the nature of its result
okay can you by the way the name of the
third one did I give you
yeah no no hopes no wishes okay can you
give the gasoline example in terms of
these three yeah that's a difficult the
car running right now is the second one
the gasoline that you put into it before
you left
Buie it's the first one and reaching to
sun is the third one I'll start the car
running on the highway is to the car
getting gas in Bouie
if the gas station is open and if they
have any gas
good luck is number one cars and then
reaching to Sun is number three how's
that okay but actually all things are
all three okay thank you okay
clouds seven meanings we got 15 minutes
you okay you don't need booboo dumb
and you can make good but where you are
okay
let's talk about the Sanskrit word up
hum okay up up is an ancient word for
water AP in ancient Sanskrit is a word
for water
okay still in Hindi you can say up kind
of high yeah don't even know but I doubt
it means thank you for the glass of
water up okay
ap that comes for a longer word acaba
acaba and the ke drop down okay became
up guess what Akbar came a Gua in
Spanish aqua filter aqua okay water
Brum Brum means to carry something okay
the word bear a burden the word burden
comes from that you want a bad word
Katie's like yeah I can use it on Adam
on the way home but Bertha in Sanskrit
means wife the wife why because you have
to it's you have to the husband has to
carry it in ancient times nowadays the
husband is the birther and the wife has
to carry the husband these are good
times for men all the women are working
okay anyway that's birthday so Burmese
to carry so what's up from water carrier
which is a clown okay got it up from
cool okay cloud carrier it's right water
carrier okay this one's tough this one's
tough you have to learn a new idea okay
which is why you're here and that's my
job
[Music]
after you see emptiness directly is it
still possible to get mad at your
husband yeah that means okay
never forget for you to get mad at
somebody for you to get upset at
somebody requires that you misunderstand
them okay you must feel that they are
coming this way okay the moment you
understand that your husband was created
because you yelled at your kids last
week it's impossible to get upset at
anybody except yourself the moment you
remember I cursed you I cursed you like
a week ago or 10 years ago or 20 years
ago I cursed you I taught you emptiness
you know sooner or later all the fun in
your life is gonna be finished okay you
can't get mad at anybody anymore you
can't get angry at anybody
you can't blame anybody you can't yell
at any other driver on the street I
still do okay I give them special mudra
signs and veronica's like don't do that
I'm okay it's impossible to get upset if
you remember emptiness it's coming from
me
it's kind of it's coming from me okay so
does Ania still have the seeds to see
things coming from their own side after
they come out of emptiness meditation
they do in fact you could compare them
to come on give it to me I will give you
a star
yeah you can compare them to the
magician okay they know they're crazy
but they still see the tree they still
see the horse they know where it's
coming from but they can't stop seeing
the horse okay now what's the main
difference between an aria and in our
hut are not stop the scenes they are
like the person who came later they like
the person who came out of their house
after the powder was thrown
okay they're like why is everybody
excited there's I don't see anything
okay that's our hot okay so when you
reach our heart the difference between
Aria and our heart in bodhisattva level
8 the difference between body self a
level one where you see emptiness
directly and buddy softer level or
number eight is that you removed the
seeds to see stuff coming from their own
son okay in our heart who walks okay so
the lady who came home and saw the
second husband in the kitchen must have
been at best in Aria she's the one who
ran in the bathroom and yelled at the
person in the mirror was an aria I would
say that the one who came home and got
upset didn't understand that one is a
child infant okay and we're gonna learn
some there's a teenager also but that's
in the fourth part of the diamond cutter
there's a thing called a teenager
you guys are teenagers okay and okay so
the are how it's supposed to have no
more scenes but what's the dirt street
are hot in a Buddha yeah buddy soft
level nine buddy self at level ten you
become a Buddha and then you can see all
things
you can see all things now there's a
thing called trace a thing called a
trace a trace after you reach lower or
hot you remove all Sun scars or or
vasana seeds to see things the wrong way
but in but I'll give you a new idea okay
between our heart and Buddha there's a
thing called traces traces it means
traces of the bad seeds they don't have
bad seeds but they have traces okay
especially lower our hands
they're called Ming and Lin in Tibet
insane a man LAN nee man then I don't
know this sounds can let me see if I can
find it
- dealer or something
yeah do stop deuce to Leah okay
in Sanskrit deuce means bad in English
its D is in Greek it's dys like
dysentery is a bad thing to get
dysfunctional okay
disappointment okay still still means
station comes from that standing comes
from
it means situation situation comes from
that okay so bad situation do she Julia
okay in Sanskrit it means a trace
subtle trace in a lower or hon okay and
they can still do slightly naughty
things in body speech and mind you want
to know what they are this is like
probably going to be in the gossip
magazines next week okay
lower our heart can still do physical
bad things like jumping in a way that
doesn't look nice for a monk to do skip
skipping okay it's called a trace
behavior trace physical behavior okay
they're supposed to walk like Buddha
but they're like okay so subtle trace
not it's not a bad thing right but it's
not quite like buna okay that's physical
verbal they can still say to other
hearts hearts you're a dork little bad
word okay it's not like other
four-letter words
Dorcas just like your silly geek you're
a geek okay they can still say little
tiny bad things to other our hearts okay
I'm taking you deeper and in their
cessation meditation they can still have
traces of disturbances okay what's a
cessation meditation it's the point in
level 9 when you remove the boo-boo Lama
in in Buddhism that's called cessation
meditation that moment in level 9 when
you remove the boo-boo Lama and there's
just the empty space there which is the
real emptiness the real clear line okay
and you're supposed to try to commune
with it right in a lower our hearts
meditation if they still have douche
Atulya they will still have slight
coming in and out of that feeling okay
very slight traces okay got it now you
understand the idea of traces for lower
our hearts physical verbal and mental by
the way in the lions dance scriptures
which I can translate and give you if I
have time because I have that it's a
hundred and fifty pages of notes just
about the Lions death I just need time
okay in the in the nine levels I told
you in level number one is called desire
around
then concentration level 1 concentration
level 2 concentration level 3
concentrations over for what's the fifth
one called endless space what's the
sixth one card and there's consciousness
what's the seventh one called Chi Yong
mate nothing you know nothing in English
nothing it's a turn off your mind
nothing
then what's what's level eight Kong yeah
not nothing and not not nothing
not thinking and not not thinking that's
number eight the name for level nine is
cessation meditation and it is named
from the moment that you wipe out the
booboo Lama okay it's named the ninth
level is named from the moment that you
wipe out the boo-boo number okay if
you're good and you're really bored one
day I'll teach you the result names for
the eight and song but do not done the
dirty tastes like very seventeen names
okay next time okay now why are we on
the subject of calling number nine
sensation meditation because we were
talking about their studious we were
talking about traces that lower our
hearts have even in that meditation even
during that meditation they get little
distractions okay because they did
little boo-boo things like they called
timid dork or something it's not a real
bad name it's not a great name okay all
right why are we on this subject because
we reached the clouds for Jamyang Sheba
the cloud represents those traces future
traces okay for Jami on Sheba the cloud
in the verse at the end of the diamond
cutter Sutra the last metaphor the first
meaning of the last metaphor is cloud
future clouds in your mind
okay future clouds in the mind even of
an our Han okay slight disturbances
during level nine okay slight
disturbances during the online
those are future clouds remember the
ninth metaphor is future stuff future
stuff you can't predict the weather you
don't know what's coming tomorrow clouds
represent the future problems future
sounds good to us
okay got it you okay was that too long
all right
don't forget Michael doing misses turn
you got a teaching next time let's do
one more and I will save the finale for
tomorrow okay by the way you can start
talking tomorrow morning when the Sun
comes up there's a tradition in Buddhism
that you break up fast or you break
silence when the Sun comes up it has a
definition if you can sit with your hand
like this and you can see that the lines
on your hand the Sun just came up so
when we go to Thailand we're gonna take
the 1-day vow Bodhisattva vow
Allyson's translating the Terek she's
going to teach it and you're allowed
you're not supposed to eat you're
supposed to finish your meal by 12
o'clock okay which is what monks and
nuns are supposed to do okay you're
supposed to finish your meal on that day
in Thailand by 12 o'clock okay
then I like to tell the story of my
friend dr. Taylor I I went to his room
the next morning before dawn and he was
sitting at the window and he had his
hand like this and he had a box of
chocolate chip cookies in his other hand
I like dr. Taylor what are you doing I'm
waiting for the Sun yeah he was kind of
chubby guy still kind of tell me guy
okay
he said eighty he's 85 he's still
working on ACIP okay cool
all right so number two I'll give you
I'll give you the next three four right
fine oh six how many are in there oh
seven total okay I owe you six more
tomorrow okay I owe you six more
tomorrow okay then we're done if we have
time I'll take you to some of the other
suitors where the Buddha taught the same
verse and two at Tantra college chakra
Tantra where he gave three more for
dessert that's your dessert okay then I
we have to do the last part of Sutra
next time okay cuz this lightning was so
slow we have a we want to do some songs
for you tomorrow so we're gonna practice
after this class so if you can go eat
breakfast for an hour and a half okay
and you know enjoy silence and we're
gonna practice some songs I like to play
a song for veronica's every every time
it makes me happy okay so Scott has a
question
oh I'm sorry okay three Veda means
knowledge of the two Vedas
Vijay means born again okay all right
he's the director of our Sanskrit
program and he's building the Sanskrit
School where you're going to study in
Varanasi which is the mother of all
Sanskrit knowledge in the world it's
right there we were lucky we got a
chance some guy had to marry his
daughter and he needed money really bad
John Brady jumped on it